Ahmed Mohamed Reda

Front-End Developer

ΩΠΩ

(+20) 1145809984

□ asayed565565@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Mid-Leve front-end with 2 years of experience building websites and web applications using ReactJS and modern JavaScript tools/frameworks, seeking a challenging and rewarding position as a fullstack developer where I can apply my skills in programming to deliver high-quality solutions.

♀ Giza

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Commerce English section

2016-2020 Cairo University Accounting department GPA: 2.8 (70%)

Front End Developer (React.js) October 2023 - February 2024 Route Academy

EXPERIENCE

Front-end Developer (intern.)

March 2024 – April 2024

Prodigy InfoTech

- Assisting in Front-end Development: Collaborating with the development team to create and modify web interfaces using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Documentation and Code Maintenance: Documenting code changes, writing clear and concise comments, and maintaining code repositories for future reference.

Merchandise Developer & Help Desk

February 2021 - December 2023

ACTIV ABOU ALAA

- **Merchandise Developer & control**
 - Review & check the new merchandise and collect data
 - Adjustment prices of the merchandise on the program
 - Main member of the stocktaking committee
- **Help Desk**
 - Follow-up computers for employees

- Ensuring security and efficiency of IT infrastructure
- Install and configure software and hardware
- Set up accounts and workstations

System Administration

February 2018 – June 2020

JEL ACTIV

- Installing and configuring software, hardware and networks
- Monitoring system performance and troubleshooting issues
- Ensuring security and efficiency of IT infrastructure
- Install and configure software and hardware
- Monitor performance and maintain systems according to requirements

PERSONAL ACHIEVEMENT

#louvreinnovations

Overview: site for interior decoration works for a company, displaying their bio &

projects

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

#Yummy

Overview: Discover new and interesting cooking recipes on this website! The website offers a diverse range of recipes organized by region, ingredient, and meal type, making it easy to find exactly what you're looking for.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, API, jQuery

#Egyptian party

Overview: a simple responsive website using jQuery

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, iQuery

#Weather App

Overview: The Weather-Forecast JS app is a user-friendly web tool for checking real-time weather forecasts. Developed with, it uses a weather API to provide users with essential details like temperature, and wind speed. And geolocation API to access the user's location information with their permission.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, API

#Login APP

Overview: A simple App This system consists of:

- 1- Sign-up form for users to register with a unique email address, name, and password.
- 2- Sign-in form for logging in with email and password.
- 3- The home page displays the user's name upon successful sign-in.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Font Awesome

#Bookmarker

Overview: A user-friendly website URL bookmarker that easily saves and organizes your favorite websites.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Font Awesome, CRUD Logic

#Random Quotes

Overview: The JS application generates random quotes.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

#DANIAL

Overview: The portfolio site, is a fully responsive website featuring seven sections and a

user-friendly navbar

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

TRAINING - COURSES

Online Courses

- IT Help desk - Web Development (El-Zero) - Master Python (El-Zero)

Python Diploma [Flask-Django Frameworks]

September 2022 – December 2022

IT Sharks

SKILLS

Software Skills:

Languages: Python - HTML – CSS - Java Script - SCSS - TypeScript

- **Libraries:** React.js – jQuery

- **Frameworks:** Bootstrap

- **Tools:** GitHub - VS Code - Figma

Language skills:

Arabic [Mother tongue] - English [Very Good]

Personal skills:

- Problem solving skills. - Team player

- Excellent Communication Skills - Research & Analysis

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

- Date of birth: 16th May 1998 - Military status: Exempted